（白俄罗斯 明斯克）
班吉
Benji.
班吉 你听到了吗
Benji, do you copy?
班吉
Benji.
噢 该死
Oh. Shit.
伊森在哪儿
Where's Ethan?
我现在没空跟你聊
Uh. I can't talk right now.
东西已经上飞机了
The package is on the plane.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们正在制定第二方案
We're currently formulating
虽然严格上来说 这已经是第三方案
a plan B although technically, it's a plan C.
事情进展的不太顺啊
This isn't going very well.
我也知道 勃兰特 你这么说也无济于事
I am aware of that, Brandt. You're not helping.
伊森究竟在哪里
Where's Ethan?
我不知道 我们已经关闭了无线电联络
I don't know. We're on radio silence.
东西在飞机上 不能让它就这么起飞
That plane cannot takeoff, with the package on it.
- 你明白吗 - 我们正想办法呢
- You understand? - We're working on it.
卢瑟 你跑那去干什么
Luther? What the hell are you doing there?
你应该在马来西亚执行任务才对
You are supposed to be on an assignment in Malaysia.
我是在马来西亚 已经来了两天了 班吉需要我的帮助
I'm in Malaysia, I've been here 2 days. Benji needed my help.
我不需要帮助 我只是…
I didn't need help. I just…
需要协助 完全两回事好吗
I needed assistance, it's a different thing.
东西还在飞机上呢
The package is still on that plane.
我们知道东西还在飞机上
We understand the package is on the plane.
我们正在尝试通过远程控制破坏他们的系统
We're trying to cripple it remotely.
你可以做到的吗
You can do that.
只要飞行员还开着卫星上行链接就可以
We can if the pilot left the satellite uplink switch on.
- 而他确实没关闭 - 你是怎么接入卫星上行链接的
- Which he has. - And how do you access the uplink?
这就需要黑进一颗俄罗斯卫星了
It involves hacking a Russian satellite.
这我可不会批准
I can't authorise that.
所以我也没征求同意
Which is why I didn't ask permission.
我们正因为违规操作被调查呢
We are under investigation for misconduct.
可东西都在飞机上了 你还要我怎么做
The package is on-board. What do you want me to do?
卢瑟
Uh. Luther.
我观察到热反应了 班吉 引擎开始发动了
I'm reading a heat bloom, Benji. The engines are starting.
是的 我也发现了
Yeah. I'm aware of that.
但是在连上卫星之前 我什么都做不了
But I can't do anything until I'm connected to the satellite.
- 班吉 连上了 - 好 太棒了
- Benji, you are connected. - Okay, Great.
东西还在那架飞机上
The package is still on that plane.
关掉燃料泵
Shut down the fuel pump.
机械控制系统都被锁死了
Uh. Mechanical are lockdown.
- 那电子控制系统呢 - 噢 那倒是可能会有效
- What about the electrical system? - Oh, that might work.
不 不
No. No.
- 液压系统 - 好 我试试
- Hydraulics. - Okay, standby.
不行 被加密了
No, they're encrypted.
班吉 飞机要起飞了
Benji, the plane.
我知道 东西还在上面呢
Yes! The package is on the plane!
我们都清楚
We get it!
你能把舱门打开么
Can you open the door?
- 伊森你在哪里 - 我就在飞机旁边
- Ethan? Where are you? - I'm by the plane.
班吉 你能把舱门打开么
Benji, can you open the door?
我能不能把舱门打开 也许可以
Uh. Can I open the door? Uh. Maybe.
等我给你信号 你就把舱门打开
Open the door when I tell you.
我在飞机上了 快点开门
I'm on the plane. Open the door.
你是怎么进到飞机里去的
How did you get in the plane?
我没在飞机里面 我是在飞机上面
Not in the plane, I'm on the plane!
快开门
Open the door!
班吉 把门打开
Benji. Open the door!
是 是 是 好的
Yeah-yeah-yeah… Okay, okay.
- 班吉 现在立刻把门打开 - 我在努力
- Benji, open that door right now! - Yeah, I am trying.
- 快点啊 班吉 - 班吉 快点开门
- Come on, Benji. - Benji, open that door!
加油 加油 加油啊
Come on. Come on. Come on.
拜托了 很好 搞定了
Come on. Yes, got it.
不是那扇门
That's the wrong door!
班吉 不是那扇门 是另外一扇
Benji, not that door. The other door.
另一扇 好的 另一扇
The other door. Right. Yes, the other door.
好了 是 对不起 我的错 我的错
Okay, yes, yes. Sorry, sorry. My bad, my bad.
你去看看
Check it out.
好了 我要把跳伞门打开了
Alright. Look, I'm gonna open the para-door.
这下怎么样
How's that?
《碟中谍5：神秘国度》
（英国 伦敦）
我们要打烊了
We're about to close.
我不会待很久的
I won't be long.
你有什么特别想买的碟吗
You looking for anything in particular.
非常少见的碟
Something rare.
我来猜猜
Let me guess.
古典
Classical.
爵士
Jazz.
- 萨克斯风 - 柯川演奏
- Sax. - Coltrane.
- 钢琴呢 - 蒙克
- Piano. - Monk.
贝斯手魅影·威尔逊
Shadow Wilson on the bass.
魅影·威尔逊是鼓手
Shadow Wilson played drums.
知道为什么要叫他魅影吗
Know why they called him Shadow?
因为他的鼓点轻柔
Because he had a light touch.
你运气很好
You're in luck.
我这有一张首发版唱片
I've a first pressing.
真的是你本人
It really is you.
我听说过你的故事
I've heard stories.
不会都是真的吧
They can't all be true.
晚上好 亨特先生
Good even, Mr. Hunt.
你从白俄罗斯带回的武器
The weapons you recovered
已经被确认是VX神经毒气
in Belarus were confirmed to be VX nerve gas.
其威力足以摧毁一座大型城市
Capable of devastating a major city.
在飞机降落于大马士革之后不到24小时
The bodies of the air crew were found less than
我们就找到了机组人员的尸体
24 hours after they landed in Damascus.
经确认他们的身份为普通车臣独立武装分子
They were identified as low level Chechen separatist.
他们并没有能力或权限
With neither the access nor the ability
接触他们运送的这些武器
to acquire the weapons they were transporting.
这也印证了你之前的怀疑
This would support your suspicion
有一个秘密组织在那些对西方利益集团交好的国家中
that a shadow organization is committed to inciting revolution.
通过恐怖主义行动
By enabling acts of terror
来煽动革命
in nations friendly to Western interests.
碟中谍小组怀疑这个组织与你去年一直在追查的那个
IMF suspects this to be the same shadow organization
是同一个秘密组织
you have been tracking for the last year
也就是所谓的辛迪加
Also known as the Syndicate.
碟中谍小组猜对了
IMF would be right.
通常情况下 你和你的组员会被派去
Normally, you and your team would be tasked
渗透并摧毁这个恐怖分子网络
with infiltrating and disrupting this terrorist network,
但是我们已经采取措施确保这不会发生
but we have taken steps to ensure that this will not happen.
因为我们就是辛迪加 亨特先生
Because, we, are the Syndicate, Mr. Hunt.
而现在我们也知道你的真实身份
And now we know who you are.
你可以选择是否接受你的任务
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
那就是直面你的命运
is to face your fate.
继续追查我们 你会被抓住 跟我们做对 你就会被干掉
Pursue us, you'll be caught. Resist us, you'll be killed.
而你敬重的部长大人
And you precious Secretary
根本不会承认任何与你行动有关的事情
will disavow any knowledge of your actions.
祝你好运 亨特先生
Good luck, Mr. Hunt.
这个留言会在五秒中后自毁
This message will self destruct in 5 seconds.
（华盛顿特区）
主席先生
Mr. Chairman, the IMF's
碟中谍小组的违规行为都可以追溯到我刚到中央情报局的时候
misadventures date back to my earliest days in the CIA
当时他们潜入中情局
when the IMF broke into
窃取我们的一份秘密特工名单
the CIA to steal a list of covert operatives.
而最近 居然搞起了一枚俄罗斯弹头
And now, more recently a Russian warhead.
是解除了危险的俄罗斯弹头
Disarmed Russian warhead.
- 一枚俄罗斯核弹头 - 碟中谍小组出手 安全保证
- A Russian nuclear warhead. - Branded safe by the IMF.
在其掉落进旧金山湾之前
Clipped the Transamerica Pyramid
从泛美金字塔上砸穿了过去
before plunging into the San Francisco bay.
西岸的空气质量幸免于难
Saving the western atmosphere.
而这一切的起因 都是因为碟中谍小组的特工故意将
This made possible by IMF agents who did willing
导弹发射密码透漏给一个恐怖分子
provide the launch codes to a known terrorist.
我说对了吗 勃兰特特工
Do I have that right, agent Brandt?
在没有获得部长的许可之前
I can neither confirm nor deny details
我既不能承认也不能否认这些行动的细节
of any such operation without Secretary's approval.
就在同一周内 碟中谍小组还潜入了克里姆林宫
This was the same week after IMF infiltrated the Kremlin.
这是潜入前的克里姆林宫
Here's the Kremlin before.
这是之后的景象
And the Kremlin after.
我既不能承认也不能否认这些行动的细节
I can neither confirm nor deny details of any operation…
在没有获得部长的许可之前 是的 我们知道
Without the Secretary's approval. Yes, we know.
也就是说 在陪审团任命一位新的部长之前
In fact, until this panel appoints a new Secretary,
你就不能跟我们透露任何事情 对吧 勃兰特特工
you really can't say much of anything, can you, agent Brandt?
不是我定的规矩 亨利先生
Well. I didn't write the rules, Mr. Hunley.
主席先生 这个所谓的碟中谍小组
Mr. Chairman, the so call Impossible Missions Force
不仅肆意妄为 而且观念过时
is not just a rogue organization, it is an outdated one.
简直就像一个体制没有透明公开和监管不利时代的产物
A throwback to an era without transparency and without oversight.
- 主席先生 - 是时候解散碟中谍小组了
- Mr. Chairman. - The time has come to dissolve the IMF.
- 主席先生 - 然后把其资源和人员调拨给中情局
- Mr. Chairman. - And transfer the salvageable assets to the CIA.
主席先生
Mr. Chairman, the IMF has
碟中谍小组这四十年来都在没有监管的情况下运作的
operated without oversight for 40 years.
- 它的方式是不是不正规呢 是的 - 主席先生
- Now, are its methods unorthodox? Yes. - Mr. Chairman.
结果是不是有时也不尽完美呢 当然会
Are its results less than perfect? Absolutely.
但是没有碟中谍小组 我们只好…
But without the IMF, to be force…
我们就会有稳定和秩序
There'll be order and stability.
没有碟中谍小组…
Without the IMF…
陪审团认可碟中谍小组对于国际安全的贡献
This panel recognizes the IMF's contribution to global security.
但是中情局局长亨利所举出的事件
But the events laid out by CIA director Hunley
确实揭露了你们蓄意铤而走险的边缘政策
also show a pattern of once and brinkmanship
还有对政策协议的完全无视
and a total disregard for protocol.
在我看来
From where I sit,
你们不合规定的行动方式和冒险没有什么区别
you unorthodox methods are indistinguishable from chance.
而结果 无论好还是坏
And your results, perfect or not,
看起来更像是在赌运气
looked suspiciously like luck.
而今天恐怕就是碟中谍小组运气用光的时候了
I'm afraid today is the day when the IMF's luck runs out.
你来干吗
What are you doing here?
"What are you doing here?"
我很好奇他看上你什么了
What does he see in you, I wonder.
他是谁
Who is he?
让我们看看你到底是不是铁打的
I want to see what is done.
要不你帮我解开手铐
Why don't you take off the cuffs.
我会让你见识见识的
And I'll show you.
文特
Vinter.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am?
贾尼克·文特
Janik Vinter.
他们也叫你 骨科医生
They call you, the bone doctor.
有趣的是
The funny thing is.
官方三年前就宣布你死亡了
You're officially declared dead, 3 years ago.
顺便说一句 鞋子不错
Nice shoes by the way.
不是他的
Not his.
你的
Yours.
我们收到的指示是跟他谈谈
We have instructions to talk,
而不是杀了他
not to kill him.
让人开口的方式因人而异
There are men who can be broken in different ways.
这家伙是个硬汉
This one's a fighter.
在你策反他之前 他宁可去死
He'll die, before you turn him.
你是在担心他会取代你的位置对吗
Are you worry he's gonna take your place?
你先走吧 等会儿场面会很难看的
You should go, before it gets ugly.
没错 他说的对
Yeah, he's right.
你可以走了
You should go.
那我们就来看看你到底有多难搞
Now, let's see how tough you are.
是吗 贾尼克
Do you, Janik.
我们之前并没有见过 对吧
We've never met before, right?
跟我来
Follow me.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
- 你在搞什么 - 我不能走
- What're you doing? - I can't leave.
听着 你不能留下 我们刚杀了那些人
Look. You can't stay. We just killed those men.
不是我们杀的 是你
We didn't kill them. You did.
我试着阻止你 你却逃走了
I tried to stop you. You got away.
你是谁
Who are you?
你现在最好赶紧走 祝你好运
You better hurry now. Good luck.
不 等等
No, wait. Wait!
他在哪
Where is he?
他往北边通道去了 还把门关上了
He's heading towards north passage. He has closed the gate.
快追 他就要跑远了 快
Run. He's getting away. Hurry!
- 七号通信栈 - 西欧 非加密线路
- Stack-com 7. - Western Europe unsecured.
- 代码 - BE11
- Designator. - Bravo Echo One One.
连接中
Connecting.
- 我是勃兰特 - 线路加密
- This is Brandt. - Go secure.
说吧
Go.
伦敦分支遭遇入侵 重复 伦敦分支遭遇入侵
London terminal is compromised. Repeat, London is compromised.
特工据点已经沦陷 请求允许立即撤离
Agent placed is down. Request immediate extraction.
发生了什么事情 是谁攻破了伦敦分支
What happened? Who breached London?
有什么可以追查下去的线索
Do you've anything to go on?
我看到那人的脸了 他想要东西 但不是信息
A face. He wanted something. Not information.
他本可以杀了我 可是他没有
He could've kill me, but he didn't.
- 好 你觉得那意味着什么 - 辛迪加是真实存在的
- Okay, what do you think it means. - The Syndicate is real.
他们知道我们的真实身份 我们如何执行任务
They know who we're, how we operate.
我想我知道为什么追查他们会那么难了
I think I know why they've been so hard to find.
尽可能的搜集所有能查到的
Just focus operations on gathering
前秘密特工信息
any available Intel regarding formal covert operatives.
不管是哪个国家或者机构
It doesn't matter what country or agency.
只要查死亡 或者是推测死亡的
Just as long as they are dead Or presumed dead.
从贾尼克·文特入手 他也被叫做骨科医生
Start with Janik Vinter. He's also known as the bone doctor.
- 我没法查了 - 什么
- I can't do that. - What?
你说的什么意思
What're you talking about?
委员会关闭了行动组
The Committee has shut us down.
所有的行动都被移交给了中情局
Operations are to be handled over to the CIA.
碟中谍小组已经不复存在了
There is no more IMF.
我被命令召回所有的人
I've been ordered to bring everyone in.
- 伊森 - 我明白了
- Ethan. - I understand.
- 伊森 - 我明白 勃兰特
- Ethan. - I understand, Brandt.
就当我们从来没有过刚才的对话
We didn't have this conversation.
我在伦敦消失了 你不知道我去哪里了
I disappeared in London. You don't know where I am.
也不知道我是死是活
If I'm dead or alive.
你看到的那个人 你能找到他么
This man you saw. Can you find him?
不找到他我是不会罢休的
I won't stop until I do.
这很有可能是我们的最后一次任务了 伊森
This may very well be our last mission, Ethan.
干得漂亮点
Make it count.
勃兰特
Brandt.
既然我们很快就要开始共事了
Since we are going to be work together,
我希望你能慎重地回答我的问题
I want you to choose your next words very carefully.
亨特在哪里
Where is Hunt?
- 我不知道 - 别对我撒谎 勃兰特
- I don't know. - Don't lie to me, Brandt.
我根本联系不上他
I have no way of contacting him.
他潜伏的很深 最后一次得到消息是 他在追查辛迪加
He's deep cover. Last I heard, he's tracking the Syndicate.
我们开门见山地说
Let's cut the bull.
你很清楚我们是谁 也很明白我们的能力
You know who we are. You know what we are capable of.
关于这个辛迪加
How come the CIA has never
中情局怎么可能从没发现任何可靠情报
discovered any actual Intel regarding this Syndicate.
- 你想暗示什么 - 不是暗示 是陈述
- What are you implying? - Not implying, stating.
其实也在提出一个指控
Leveling an accusation actually.
亨特扮演着纵火犯和消防员的双重身份
Hunt is both arsonist and fireman at the same time.
我相信辛迪加只是他靠想象所捏造出来的产物
I believe that the Syndicate is a figment of his imagination.
用来证明碟中谍小组存在的必要性
Created to justify the IMF's existence.
我会找到他 勃兰特 到那个时候
I'm going to find him, Brandt. And when I do,
我一定会让他为他的
he will be called upon to answer
每一次蓄意破坏的行动负责
for every wanton active mayhem he's responsible for.
欢迎加入中情局
Welcome to the CIA.
你永远都找不到他的
You'll never find him.
等着瞧吧 勃兰特
Set your watch, Brandt.
伊森·亨特没几天自由自在的日子了
Ethan Hunt is living his last day as a free man.
（六个月后）
（古巴 哈瓦那）
（中央情报局 弗吉尼亚州 兰利）
好了 大家 注意
All right, everybody. Heads up.
就是今天了
This is it.
阿尔法队准备好了 随时待命
Alpha team prep. Standing by.
- 执行吧 - 执行小队 开始行动
- Execute. - Langley brimstone, go.
我再重复一次 开始行动
I say again. We are a go.
总部 这里没有人
Langley, there's nobody here.
执行小队 镜头对向北面的墙
Langley brimstone. Face the north wall.
又一个在此消失的是航班606
Another one vanishes here is flight 606?
战火再燃 化学武器要上了
Fire guts chemical weapons plant
世界银行宣布出现危机
World bank declares crisis
（班吉·邓恩 亲启）
邓恩
Dunn.
又到那个的时间了吗 好吧
Is it that time already. Okay.
我会问你一组比照问题
I'm going to ask you a series of control questions.
我知道 也会诚实的回答
I know and I'm gonna answer truthfully.
然后你还会问我一些让我故意撒谎的问题
And then you gonna ask me to lie intentionally.
- 你的名字是 - 挪威的国王
- State your name. - The King of Norway.
看到了吧 这就是撒谎
See, that's a lie.
其实我是王位的第三顺位继承人
I'm actually third in line to the throne.
我的哥哥是
My brother was…
- 伊森·亨特跟你联系过么 - 他为什么要联系我
- Has Ethan Hunt contacted you? - Why would he contact me?
亨特重新露面了 这次在古巴
Hunt has resurfaced. This time in Cuba.
他 留下了这些
He… left these behind.
告诉我你怎么看这些东西
Tell me what you make of them.
我不知道 他开始玩剪贴薄了吗
I don't know. He's taken up scrap booking?
看看这些照片 邓恩
Look at the photographs, Dunn.
所有人要么失踪要么死了 每一个都是
All of them are either missing or dead, everyone.
他们全部都曾经是政府特工
All of them were government agents.
俄罗斯 法国 英国 以色列 你能叫出名字的
Russian, French, British, Israelis, you name it.
这些文件都是高度机密
These are highly classified
但是亨特却毫不费力的就搜集到了
files and yet Hunt had no problem collecting them.
而他好像总是比我们要快一步
And he always seems to be a step ahead of us.
- 我在想这是为什么 - 你是在暗示我在帮他吗
- I wonder how? - Are you suggesting I'm helping him?
我的确有过这个想法
That thought had cross my mind.
六个月以来 我一直待在这里
6 months, I have been here.
筛选堆积如山的元数据和百兆位编码
Sifting through mountains of metadata and exabytes of encoded excrement.
我破解 处理 分析的数据是我们部门最多的
I had decrypted, processed, passed more data than anyone in my section.
而每周 你都把我带到这儿来
And yet every week, you hold me in here.
换着各种方式 问我同一个问题
And you ask me the same question, just in a different way.
然而今天 你并没有回答我
And today, you haven't answered it.
你总觉得 某种程度上 我对他还有义务和责任
You seem to thinks I have some kind of obligation to him.
但实际上 并不是这样
Okay, nothing could be further from the truth.
伊森·亨特依旧在逃
Ethan Hunt is still out there in the field,
而我却被困在这里要对他的所作所为负责
and I am stuck here answering for it.
我们并不是朋友
We're not friends.
我不欠他什么
I owe him nothing.
今天就到此为止吧 邓恩
That'll be all, Dunn.
（奥地利 维也纳）
欢迎来到维也纳 班吉 有想念我吗
Welcome to Vienna, Benji. Missed me?
伊森你在哪儿 你到底死到哪里去了
Ethan, where are you? Where the hell have you been?
没有行踪 算了 拜托 别告诉我啦
No act… you know what? Please, don't tell me that,
不然我在每周的例行测谎中又要多说一个谎了
because it's just another thing I would have to lie about in my weekly polygraph.
你什么都不必担心 继续往前走
Everything is going to be fine. Just keep walking.
但是 要确保你没有被跟踪
But, make sure you're not being followed
所以这些歌剧门票不是我中奖赢的 对吧
Oh. I didn't win those opera tickets, did I?
不 恐怕不是
No, I'm afraid not
- 那么我们去哪儿见面 - 我们不见面
- So, where do we meet? - We don't.
为你着想 不能让人看到我们在一起见过面
For your sake, we shouldn't be seen together.
你有一封邮件
You have mail.
- 他是谁 - 我们来这里要找的人
- Who is he? - That's what we're here to find out.
据我所知 他是我们探查辛迪加的唯一线索
What I do know, is he's our only possible link to the Syndicate
并且我有理由相信 他今晚也会出现在这里
and I have reason to believe that he's going to be here tonight.
但我一个人找不到他 你要入伙吗
But I can't find him alone. Are you in?
- 你要不要入伙 - 当然 当然
- Are you in? - Yes, of course. Of course.
- 计划是什么 - 很简单 你找到他 我们跟踪他
- So, what's the play? - Simple. You find him, we tag him.
- 我会对他紧追不舍 - 在这之后呢
- I follow him wherever he goes. - And after that?
之后你周一早上飞回去上班
After that you're on a plane, back at work Monday morning.
- 神不知鬼不觉 - 什么 这就没了
- No one is the wiser. - What? That's it?
你的处境已经够危险的了
You're in enough danger as it is.
我本不想把你卷进来 可惜我别无选择
I didn't want to involve you this much but I had no choice.
既然你都让我卷入这一切了
Whoa. If you're gonna bring me all this way,
至少安排点更… 刺激的剧情
you could at least give me something a little be more…you know, dramatic.
班吉 我们都要努力保持低调
Benji, we are trying to keep a low profile.
你想来点刺激的剧情 去看歌剧吧
You want drama, go to the opera.
- 你可以看到我眼前的这一切吗 - 可以
- Are you seeing what I'm seeing? - Yes, I am.
我猜那位就是奥地利总理
Am I correct in assuming that is the Chancellor of Austria?
- 回答正确 - 你知道他会来这儿吗
- Yes, you are. - Did you know he's going to be here?
- 不知道 - 好吧
- No - Right.
现在这里来了位欧洲国家的元首
Well. We have a European Heads of State here,
与此同时 我们在搜捕一个穷凶极恶的恐怖分子
at the same time as we're looking for a nefarious terrorist.
- 我相信这两者毫无联系 - 班吉
- And I'm sure the two things are completely unrelated. - Benji.
而同时 我还得努力忘掉
Meanwhile I'll try and overlook the fact that
- 你正被中情局全球通缉的事实 - 班吉
- you're an international fugitive wanted by the CIA. - Benji.
- 还有这次未经批准的行动可能会被定性为叛国 - 班吉
- And this little unsanctioned operation is tenemented treasonous. - Benji.
因为就像你之前说的
Because as you stated earlier,
周一早上我还得回到办公桌前打游戏
I will be back in my desk on Monday morning,
让一切神不知鬼不觉
playing video games and no one will be any be the wiser.
- 演出快开始了 班吉 - 知道
- The show's about to start, Benji. - Right.
- 先去找个位子 告诉我发现了什么 - 好的
- Just take your position, tell me what you see. - Okay.
顺便说一句 礼服很好看
Nice tux, by the way.
舞台就位 灯光准备
Stage is set. Ready lights.
灯光就位
Ready lights.
最后准备就位
The final preparations ready.
保持警惕
Stay alert, please.
加入碟中谍小组 监控全球
Join the IMF. See the world, on a monitor
虽然是在储藏室
in a closet.
我搞定监视器了
Okay, I have eyes.
正在搜索
Searching
- 汇报情况 班吉 - 没有进展 待命
- Talk to me, Benji. - Nothing yet. Standby.
我知道你在这儿 到底在哪儿
I know you're here. Where're you.
伊森有点状况 不能确定
Uh Ethan, I might have something for you. Can't confirm.
- 哪儿 - 后台 我给你指路
- Where? - Backstage, I will direct you
进入你左手边的门 他应该处于你的正前方
Take the door on your left. He should be right in front of you.
- 班吉 你看到了吗 - 看到什么
- Benji, did you see that? - See what?
一个女人
A woman.
什么女人 你在哪儿
What woman? Where're you?
我看不到你
I can't see you.
- 什么情况 - 我不知道
- What happened? - I don't know
伊森能听见吗 伊森 请回话
Ethan, do you copy? Ethan, come in.
伊森注意灯光控制室 伊森能听见吗
Ethan, the lighting booth. Ethan, do you copy?
噢 我的天啦
Oh god.
只是轻伤
It's a flash wound.
非常抱歉 女士们先生们
Sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
封锁这栋建筑 守住所有出口
Surround the building. Secure the exits.
我有办法出去 有兴趣吗
I've a way out. Interested?
带路
Lead the way.
- 你有话要告诉我的吗 - 现在不是时候
- Anything you want to tell me? - No, not right now.
- 能跟得上吗 - 不用等我
- How's the pace? - Don't wait for me.
下一步呢
What's next?
好吧
Alright.
这边
There.
鞋子
Shoes.
帮我鞋子脱了 拜托
Shoes, please.
要是你出了什么事…
If anything happens to you…
我什么事也不会发生
Nothing is going to happen to me.
停车
Stop the car!
上车
Get in.
快 快 快
Go go go.
我靠 她刚才拿枪指着我
What the… She tried to shoot me.
这不代表她就是坏人
It doesn't make her a bad person.
- 我恐怕必须要搜一下你的身 - 你必须得放我走
- I'm gonna have to search you. - You have to let me go.
噢 这可没门
Oh oh. Not a chance.
我以为你的职责是留守伦敦 现在你好像有点越界
I assume you're deep cover back in London but isn't this taking the role a little too far.
先等等 你认识她
Hang on a minute, you know her?
我们还没有正式地自我介绍过
Oh. We haven't formerly introduced.
但我确定她是英国特工
But I am pretty sure she's British intelligence.
伊尔莎·福斯特 你是伊森·亨特
Ilsa Faust. You're Ethan Hunt.
呃 这个颜色的唇膏可是很难买到的
And… that shade is very hard to find.
- 你今晚在歌剧院干什么 - 除了暗杀总理还有别的吗
- What were you doing at the opera tonight? - What? Aside from killing the Chancellor.
在伦敦救你的事 让我陷入了
Saving your life in London put me in a tight spot
非常危险的处境
with some very dangerous people.
我奉命前来刺杀总理 以重新赢得他们的信任
I was sent to kill the Chancellor to regain their trust.
所以你承认刺杀他了
Ha. So, you admit that you killed him?
我只想装个样子 不是真的
I went through the motion, that's not the same thing.
你本想让总理受伤住院 以此来救他一命
You thought you put him in the hospital, take him out of harm's way.
就像你打算做的那样
The same thing you tried to do.
你不会就这样相信她吧 那她的同伙呢
You're not gonna believe that, are you? What about the rest of her team?
你是指那两个蠢货 他们只是替补人员
You means those other 2 idiots? I can only assumed they were redundancies.
以防你没有奉命行事 一个人负责暗杀总理
In case you didn't follow through. One man to kill the Chancellor,
另一个杀了你 这是一个考验
the other one to kill you. A test.
多亏你 我没能杀了第二个人
Second one I failed, thanks to you.
而汽车炸弹则是最后的杀手锏
And the car bomb was insurance.
我们被人追踪了
We have a tail.
他是谁
Who is he?
我们都在追查同一个目标 而我能帮你
We're after the same thing, and I can help you.
要想打败辛迪加 你必须放我走
If you want to bring down the Syndicate, you've to let me out.
他们接近了
They're closing.
我必须看上去像是落荒而逃的 所以 快把我随便扔出去
This has to look like an escape. So, you just throw me out anywhere.
告诉我他是谁
Tell me who he is.
计划有变 把她扔出去
Oh. Change of plan. Throw her out!
你有足够的信息能找到我
You have everything you need to find me.
在我们审问班吉·邓恩关于伊森·亨特的事宜之后不到24小时
Less than 24 hours after we interviewed Benji Dunn about Ethan Hunt
他就带着门票飞去维也纳歌剧院
He was on a plane to Vienna with tickets to the opera.
他抵达剧院之后还不到六小时 总理遇刺身亡
And within 6 hours of his arrival, the Chancellor was dead.
对普通人来说 这可能只是偶然
Now, that might be circumstance to some public defendant.
但对中情局探员来说 这代表着行动情报
But to the CIA, that is actionable intelligence.
还有一种情况 他可能是为调查伊森才去的剧院
Consider the moment, the possibility that Ethan's investigation lead him to the opera.
并且他手中有这次行动的相关情报
And he's the one with the actionable intelligence.
无论如何 抓捕亨特不能再是小打小闹了
In any case, finding Hunt is no longer our pet project.
从现在起 特别行动部门将拥有最高行事的特权
The Special Activity Division will now have full discretion.
你的意思是允许就地处决
You mean shoot to kill?
亨特的生死取决于他自己的选择
Whether Hunt lives or dies. It's entirely up to him.
新身份 护照 现金 地图
New identity, passport, cash, road map.
包里有替换衣物
There's a change of clothes in that bag, right there.
所有能让你瞒天过海回到华盛顿总部的东西都在这儿了
Everything you need to make it to DC undetected.
到那儿之后 你要立即告发我
Once you're there, you'll have to inform on me.
- 我应该… 什么 - 坦白事实
- I'm suppose… what? Sorry, what? - Tell the truth.
你以为自己中了两张歌剧门票才来的维也纳
You came to Vienna believing you won 2 tickets to the opera.
我试图劝诱你参与刺杀总理的行动 被你拒绝了
And I attempted to recruit you into assassinating the Chancellor, you refused.
- 这不是事实 - 你的死活取决于他们是否相信你所说的 班吉
- That is not the true. - Your life depends on them believing you, Benji.
顺着他们的意思说 你更容易保住性命
It'll go easier if you tell them what they want to hear.
伊森 至少告诉我这一切到底是怎么一回事
Ethan, at least tell me what this is all about.
有你认识的谁吗
You recognized anyone?
- 他 - 沙特阿拉伯人 前德国特工
- Him. - He's former KSA, German intelligence.
失踪 推测已死亡
Missing, presumed dead.
他就是今晚剧院的那个人
He was at the opera tonight.
这个也是
This one too.
- 前以色列摩萨德特工 - 让我猜猜 推测已死亡
- Former Mossad. - Let me guess. Presumed dead.
今晚 我已经亲手把它变成了事实
Tonight, I made it official.
我追着他去了博斯普鲁斯
I was looking for him in Bosporus.
同一天 前来访问的马拉维共和国总统死于车祸
The same day a car accident killed the visiting President of Malawi.
在雅加达 又被他逃跑了
He slipped away again in Jakarta.
在此前几小时 一架客机在太平洋上空突然失踪
Hours before a passenger plane vanished over the Pacific
机上共计236名乘客
with 236 passengers.
之前我在菲律宾又跟丢了他
I just missed him in the Philippines.
不久之后 一座石油化工厂失火 导致两千名村民毒气中毒
Right before a fired petrochemical plant gassed a village of 2, 000 people.
你是说这些事故之间有着某种联系
You're saying these accidents are somehow connected.
那架失踪客机搭载着世界银行的总裁
That missing plane was carrying the Secretary of the World Bank.
那起火灾瓦解了一次全球军备合作
That fire bankcorrupted a global arms cooperation.
那起车祸引发了一场内战
That wreck triggered a civil war.
那些都绝非偶然
These are no accidents.
它们由某个组织策划 环环相扣 这些都是辛迪加的杰作
They're links in a chain. The work of a single organization, the Syndicate.
一个像我们一样
A rogue nation.
训练有素的秘密组织 却别有用心
Trained to do what we do. Inbuilt with a new sense of purpose.
摧毁现有秩序的制定者
Destroy the system that created them.
无论挡路的是谁
Regardless if who's in the way.
反派版的碟中谍小组
An anti-IMF.
自从亨利解散了我们部门后 这个组织就越加猖狂
And since Hunley shut us down, they've been escalating unchecked.
今晚刺杀总统的行动 就是一个声明
Killing the Chancellor tonight was a statement
宣告一个新时代的开启
The start of a new phase.
或者它们只是一系列偶发灾难
Or they could just be a series of random disasters.
他在场
He was there.
每一次都在场
Everytime.
就像今晚一样 我很确定
Just like he was there tonight. I'm sure of it.
我不知道他是谁 他来自哪里
I don't know who he is, or where he's from.
他受谁资助
How he's funded
但我知道他是一切的关键
But I know he's the key.
伊森 这就是我加入的理由
Ethan, this is what I sign up for.
- 我来帮你找到他 - 这就是为什么我带你来这儿
- Let me help you find him. - That's why I brought you here.
这是我最初的目的 但看看都发生了什么
In the first place. And look what happened.
我保护不了你
I can't protect you.
这就是为什么我需要你离开
That's why I need you to leave.
你无权决定 伊森
It's not your decision to make, Ethan.
我是外勤特工
I'm a field agent.
我知道这里面的风险 更重要的是 我还是你的朋友
I know the risks. More than that, I'm your friend.
别管我… 每周对测谎仪说了什么
No matter what I… tell the polygraph every week.
你叫我过来 因为你需要我的帮助
Now you called me because you needed my help.
现在你仍然需要 所以我要留下
And you still do. So, I'm staying.
这件事 我们就这么说定了
And that's all we're gonna say about that.
- 好吧 - 那就好
- Okay - Good
我们从哪开始
Where do we start?
伊尔莎
Ilsa.
好的 我们怎么找到她
Right. And how do we find her?
她说过用我们手中的东西可以找到她
She said we've everything we need.
我们有过协议
We had an agreement.
你派给我的任务 我会去做
You send me to do a job, I'd do it.
- 但是得按我的办法来 不是你的 - 我什么时候违约了
- But my way, not yours. - When did I deviate?
今晚你另外派了两个杀手进剧院
You put 2 more gunman at the opera tonight.
其中一个试图杀了我
One of them try to kill me.
因为你失手了
You missed.
我失手是因为伊森·亨特在那儿找你
I missed because Ethan Hunt was there looking for you.
伊森·亨特能来维也纳是因为你在伦敦放走了他
Ethan Hunt is in Vienna because you allow him escape in London.
在伦敦 文特要杀了他 这违背了你的命令
Vinter would've kill him in London and that's not what you asked for.
现在你已经两次让他逃走了
Twice now you've let him slipped away.
真是奇怪啊
Curious.
你在质疑我的忠诚 还是我的能力
Are you questioning my loyalty or my ability.
- 很难说 - 我之前告诉过你
- Can't decide. - I've told you before.
相信我 不然就杀了我
Trust me or kill me.
不过如果你要杀我 堂堂正正的来
But if you're going to kill me, be the man.
亲自动手吧
Do it yourself.
他同你说了什么吗
Did he say anything?
- 他知道摩洛哥 - 他知道摩洛哥的什么事
- He knows about Morocco. - What did he know about Morocco?
他知道那个发电站 但不知道里面有什么
He knows about the power plant. He doesn't know what's in it.
那就拜托你找到他
Find him, please.
他会来找我
He'll find me.
我已经让他看到那个了
I've him seen to that.
这个很有趣
Well, that's interesting
- 里面是什么 - 是敏感信息隔离设施
- What is it? - It's a SCIF.
保护离线状态下的电脑设备 超大容量
Secure Computer Facility offline, ultra-contained.
不可能从外部入侵
It's impossible to hack in from the outside.
实际上就像一个数据保险柜
It's essentially a digital safety deposit box.
很奇怪一名年轻女士会带着这种东西
Very strange thing for a young lady to be carrying in her sundries.
- 它在哪儿 - 摩洛哥
- Where's it located? - Morocco.
摩洛哥
Morocco.
（摩洛哥 卡萨布兰卡）
绅士们 是什么风把你们吹到了卡萨布兰卡
Now, what brings you gentlemen to Casablanca?
- 真高兴见到你 - 有什么事不能在电话里告诉我
- Good to see you - What couldn't you tell me over the telephone?
奥地利总理被刺杀了
The Chancellor of Austria was assassinated.
我们认为伊森和班吉也在现场
We believe that Ethan and Benji were there.
亨利把这件事交给特别行动小组处理了
Huntley's handed this over to Special Activities Division.
我们要赶在他们之前找到伊森
We need to find Ethan before they do.
所以才需要你
And that's where you come in.
- 没兴趣 - 听我说 卢瑟
- Not interested. - Okay. Look, Luther.
听我说 伙计 我了解伊森 但我不了解你
Look, man. I know Ethan. I don't know you.
我只知道你最后选择为亨利工作
All I know about you is that you chose to work for Hunley.
是啊 我也只知道你最后选择了辞职
Yeah, all I know about you is you chose to resign.
你不用替伊森担心
You don't have to worry about Ethan.
- 他们永远也抓不到他 - 不 他们不是要去抓住他
- They'll never catch him - No, they're not going to catch him. No.
这是中情局 我们在说的是亨利
This is the CIA, this is Hunley we're talking about.
情况已经失控了 他们要杀了他
Thing are out of control and they're going to kill him.
他们要去干掉伊森和班吉
They're going to kill Ethan. They're going to kill Benji.
我们必须抢先找到他们 你愿意来帮我吗
We have to get to them first. Are you going to help me?
有件事你要明白
You need to understand something.
伊森是我的朋友
Ethan is my friend
要是我对你的立场产生了哪怕一秒钟的怀疑
And if I have 1 second of doubt whose side you're on.
我相信你会
I believe you
- 好的 - 好的
- Alright. - Alright.
- 现在我们手上有什么 - 不多
- What do I have to go on? - Not much.
时间也不多了
And not a lot of time.
他叫所罗门·莱恩 是他创立了辛迪加
His name is Solomon Lane. He created the Syndicate.
他有什么来头
Where does he come from?
他是前英国特工
He's former British intelligence.
如果英国情报局知道辛迪加的存在
Well. If British intelligence knows the Syndicate exist,
为什么不直接通知中情局
why don't they just tell the CIA?
因为他们不想让人知道 是自己人创立了辛迪加
Because they don't want anyone knowing the Syndicate was created by one of their own.
我被秘密派遣来获得莱恩的信任
I was sent undercover to earn Lane's trust.
并且最终指认这个组织的成员们
And eventually identifying the members of his organization.
这是两年来第一次
For the first time in 2 years,
我就快要探查出他们的身份了
I'm close to knowing who they are.
莱恩有一份账册 详细记录了执行人员
Lane had a ledger. It contain the identities of his operatives,
和恐怖分子合伙人的身份 以及辛迪加内部运作情况
his terrorist associates, the entire inner workings of the Syndicate.
一个特工偷走了账册 并试图敲诈他
One of his agents stole it hoping to blackmail him.
他把账册放在一个戒备森严的电脑设备里
He kept it in a secure computer facility for safe keeping.
在拷问密码的时候 他被人失手打死了
He died being interrogated for the access code.
留给了莱恩一个大的隐患
Leaving Lane with a serious problem.
所以打垮莱恩的重要证据就被放在一个电脑里 任人来取吗
So the key to crushing Lane is sitting in a computer just waiting for someone to take it?
那么为什么莱恩不派个人来偷走账册
So why hasn't Lane just send someone to steal it?
他已经派来了 就是我
Oh, he has. He sent me.
而我能告诉你的是
And I can tell you.
这是个不可能完成的任务
It's impossible.
这个设备被藏在本地发电厂的地底 周围有军队守卫
The facility is hidden beneath the local power plant under military guard.
下载这个账册的唯一方法
And the only way to download the ledger
就是通过那地方的中央计算机终端
is through the central computer terminal, located there.
要抵达这个终端计算机 你需要通过几扇设施大门
To reach the terminal, you'll need to pass the main gates.
进入搭载装有指纹识别系统的电梯
Access the elevator with fingerprint recognition
然后分别打开三个组合密码锁
And open 3 separate combination locks.
简单 我们可以伪装成最初偷走账册的那个特工就行
Well, that's easy. We just impersonate the agent who stole the ledger in the first place.
我可以带上面具
And… I get to wear a mask.
不巧地是 即使你可以骗过其他安全检查
Unfortunately, even if you can make it through every other security measure
你骗不了最后一关
you won't beat the last one.
因为它使用的是步态分析
That's because it's protected by gait analysis.
比面部识别更加先进
A step beyond facial recognition.
这些监控知道那个特工如何行走
These cameras actually know how the agent walks,
如何说话 如何动作 甚至包括面部肌肉活动
how he talks, how he moves, right down to his facial takes.
你是说面具骗不了它
So, what you're saying is, no mask can beat it.
在我们到达地下室之前就会被识破
We're busted before we could even get into the vault.
然后我会被送进摩洛哥监狱
and lwind up in a Moroccan jail,
一辈子尽情地玩过家家的游戏
playing mummies and daddies with Ahmad the Strangler.
好吧 我放弃面具了
Okay, I don't get to wear a mask.
- 没有其他途径进入电脑室了吗 - 没有
- And there's no other way into the computer lab? - No other way in.
- 通风口呢 - 管道直径只有六英寸
- Air shaft? - 6 inch diameter pipe.
- 地基呢 - 混凝土厚达十二英尺 上下都是
- Foundation? - 12 feet of concrete, top and bottom.
- 电缆导管呢 - 这是底线
- Electrical conduit? - Bottom line is,
要想进入终端
there's no way into that terminal unless
除非把你的个人资料提前存入安全系统
your profile is pre-installed in the security system.
个人资料
Profile?
个人资料被存放在哪里
Where're the profile stored?
所有的安全数据被存放在离线的液体冷却装置里
All security data is stored offline in the liquid cooler aid.
这儿 圆环体里面有液体冷却剂
Here, inside the torus, liquid cooled.
你是说那东西在水下
You mean that thing is under water?
- 是的 - 是的
- Yes. - Yes.
好吧
Okay.
所以 要想拿到账册 必须有一个人进入那个圆环体
So, to get the ledger, one of us needs to enter the torus
替换掉其中安全资料
and change the security profile.
这样另一个人就能顺利接触到电脑
So that the other one can access the computer without being caught.
- 这就是唯一的方法 - 这就是唯一的方法
- That's the only way. - That's the only way.
我能从那儿进去吗
Can I get in through there.
- 那是什么 - 那是服务舱门
- What's that? - That's the service hatch.
它只能从内部打开 否则
It can only be opened from the inside. If you try and open it from the outside,
你会被七万加仑的高压水流击中
you'll be hit with 70, 000 gallons of pressurized water.
- 水流来自哪里 - 由进水口引入的淡化海水
- Where does the water come from? - Desalinized seawater flows through the intake.
储备在这个管道中 顺便告诉你
in the pipeline. And before you ask.
如果检测到任何金属物体进入进水口 系统就会自动关闭
The system is designed to shut down automatically if any metal enters the intake.
不能用氧气罐
No oxygen tanks.
好吧 从进水口自由潜泳到服务舱门需要多长时间
Alright. Well, how long will it take to free swim from the intake to the service hatch.
两分钟 在最佳情况下
2 minutes. With the current at full power.
那么你只需要闭气两分钟就行了
Well. Then, you just have to hold your breath for 2 minutes.
- 替换安全资料的时间呢 - 这个用最多一分钟
- What about installing the security profile? - Well. That's gonna be like a minute tops.
所以我得在水下憋气三分钟
So, I have to hold my breath for 3 minutes?
这你可以做到的啊
You can do that.
但你忽略了这个运动带来的体力消耗
But I think you're overlooking, is the physical exertion.
你的动作越激烈 你的氧气消耗就越快
The more you exert yourself, the faster you consume oxygen.
别担心他 好吗
Don't worry about him. Alright.
他只要在我进入步态分析之前 把伪造的档案导入就行了
All he has to do is install the fake profile before I get to the gait analysis.
你自己说的 这是唯一的办法
You said it yourself, it's the only way.
这也不是不可能啊
That doesn't sound impossible.
卫星监控覆盖了整个地球
Satellite over-watch covering all 7 continents,
DNA检测 脸部识别 无人侦察机和无人轰炸机
DNA profiling, facial recognition, drone surveillance, drone strikes.
你告诉我 要怎么在他们之前找到伊森和班吉
So, how are we suppose to find Ethan and Benji before they do?
我根本就不用找他们 要找的是她
I'm not even looking for them. I'm looking for her.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
这些素描 你能看出什么吗
These sketches, what do you see?
伊森自己也不清楚这人是谁
Ethan's not exactly sure who this guys is.
但这个女人 他认识
But this woman, he knows her.
伊森很信任她
He trust her.
如果他还没和这个女人在一起的话 那现在肯定还在找她
I'm betting that if he's not already with her, he's on his way.
找到她 就能找到伊森
Find her, find Ethan.
谁能看一眼面部素描就找到那个人
Tell me it's possible to pull facial recognition of a sketch.
对大多数人来说是不可能 但我在家里就能搞定
For mere mortals, no. For me, I could've done this at home.
好吧
Alright.
- 你要找多久 - 找到了
- How long is this going to take? - Found her.
卡萨布兰卡机场的监控拍到了她
CCTV picked her up at the airport in Casablanca.
怎么回事
What the hell?
这下棘手了
She's bad news.
- 请出示通行证 - 你好
- Card. - Hello.
抱歉
Sorry
- 你的通行证无效 - 班吉 我们进来了
- Your card is not working. - Benji, we're in.
谢谢
Thank you.
再说一次 你只有三分钟
One more time. You have 3 minutes.
两分半时间用来调包安全档案
2.5 minutes to switch the security profile.
剩下半分钟从服务舱口逃出来
30 seconds to escape through the service hatch.
记住 节省氧气
Remember, conserve oxygen.
水下别做多余的动作
Don't move a muscle if you don't have to.
我进电梯了
I'm in the elevator.
水流会把你带进圆环
That current will carry you to a torus.
你一到那儿 我就会关闭进水
Once you're there, I'll shut it down.
友情提示 档案放在108号箱
Important note. The profile is in slot 108.
再稍微提醒一下
And a slightly more important note,
如果我到达步态分析之前 你没有调包档案的话
if you haven't switched that profile before I reach the gait analysis,
我就会死
I'm dead.
谢谢提醒 班吉
Thank you, Benji.
- 怎么回事 - 冷却系统自动重启了
- What's the problem? - The cooling system is rebooting by itself.
系统恢复正常了
All systems' normal.
冷却系统开始运作
Cooling systems at full power.
不 不 不…
No-no-no…
没事了 你没事了
You're alright. You're okay.
你看 我说什么来着
See. What did I told you.
确实困难 但也不是不可能…
Difficult, absolutely, but certainly not impossible…
天呐 他没事吧 他怎么了 发生了什么
Jesus, is he alright? What happened? What happened?
对了 对了
Okay. Okay.
这个给你
Here.
我错怪你了
I misjudged you.
老兄 你还好吗 感觉怎么样
Hey, man. Hey. You okay? How're you doing?
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
- 班吉 - 嗯 我是班吉
- Benji. - Yes, it's Benji.
干的漂亮
You did good.
你先喘口气 好吗 歇一会儿
You take a moment, alright. Just-Just take a moment.
虽然这里没有阳光和新鲜的空气
There's nothing a little sunshine and fresh air won't fix you.
- 但你肯定会没事的 - 你在这里干嘛
- You'll be as right as rain. - What are you doing here?
听着 听着…
Look-look-look…
我们拿到了
We got it.
就知道我们会成功的
I knew we'll get it.
听着 我不想说些不好听的话
Listen. I don't want to sound ungrateful, okay.
我很感谢你所做的一切 但…
I appreciate everything you do for me, but…
总有一天 你会玩火自焚的
one of these days, you're gonna take it too far.
我们成功了
We got it.
我们要逮住那个… 呃
We're gonna nail that… Ehh.
等等
Wait. Wait.
你不是说你能找到他吗
I thought you said you can find him?
我只说过我可以定位他们在哪 想找到得靠你自己
I said I could locate him. You've to find him.
好吧
Right.
亨特在哪
Where's Hunt?
他死了
He's dead.
痛死了
Oh. That really hurts!
- 你还能走吗 - 可以
- Can you walk? - Yes, I can.
我们得赶在莱恩之前找到她
We have to get to her before Lane does.
等等 你能开车吗
Whoa-whoa-whoa… Are you okay to drive?
一分钟前你还一副要死的样子
I mean. A minute ago you were dead.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
有种不祥的预感
This is not gonna end well.
她在那
There she is!
有台阶 台阶啊
Stairs, stairs, stairs!
台阶 台阶啊
噢 该死
Ah! God damn it.
找到他们了
I found them.
搞什么啊 伙计
Oh. Come on, man.
该死
Shit.
要飙车追逐了
It's a high-speed chase.
你怎么没租辆四轮驱动的车 这下好了
You just had to get the 4 by 4, didn't you?
别怪我 是你选的车
Hey, look. Don't blame me. You chose the car.
- 明明是你一定要这辆 - 那让我来开啊
- You just had to have it! - Do you want me to drive?
- 你要让我来开吗 - 你看啊 这还是手动挡的
- Do you want me to drive? - Look, it's a stick.
你看看 你开的真慢
Look at this. Look how slow you're going.
加速啊
Speed it up.
这家伙是谁
Who's this guy?
该死
Shit!
快 快 快
Go-go-go-go. GO!
我没事 我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay. I'm okay.
他们追上来了
Here they come!
我们要怎么办
What're we gonna do?
有枪
Gun!
你系了安全带吗
Do you have your seat belts on?
什么 你现在才问我
What? You're asking me that now?
- 抓紧了 - 啊
- Hang on! - Ah!
你还好吗
Are you good?
事情… 好像有点出乎意料
Things… got a little out of hand.
啊 小心
Aw! Look out!
你还好吗
Okay. We're good?
伙计们 我错过什么了
Oh, hi boys. What did I miss?
那个好锋利 小心点
Woo. That look sharp. Careful, careful.
那我们现在怎么办
So, what do we do now?
千万别告诉我 你没备份
Please tell me, you made a copy of that disk.
当然有备份
Of course I made a copy.
那接下来我们去哪里
So where are we going?
这是个账册
It's a ledger.
存储了辛迪加的所有机密
The Syndicate's entire infrastructure.
他们的身份 受操控的政客 以及资金来源
Who they are, the politicians they control, and where the money comes from.
你想知道的都在里面
It's everything you want to know.
你怎么知道这个所谓的账册是真的
What makes you think this so-called ledger is authentic?
如果是假的 为什么莱恩这么想得到它
Why would Lane want it so badly if it wasn't authentic?
如果是真的 他又怎么会让你得到呢
Why would he ever let you have it if it was?
这难道不像是他刻意想让我拿到吗
Did you never stop to consider he may want me to have it?
伪造信息和行为诱导
Misinformation, manipulation.
可是他的强项 伊尔莎 这方面他可训练有素
It's what he does, Ilsa, it's what he's trained to do.
莱恩骗了你 你又误导了亨特
Lane lies to you, you sell his lies to Hunt.
就这样 你们俩都上当了
Together, you're both compromised.
那就是他的最终目的
That's his ultimate objective.
当然 这也可能是真的
This may be authentic.
但我只相信一个人 能帮我确认真伪 那就是你
But there's only one person I trust to verify that information. You.
我不干
No.
我的任务是带给你关于辛迪加的情报
My orders were to deliver you information regarding the Syndicate.
你的任务是打入辛迪加内部
Your orders were to infiltrate the Syndicate
我们就能得到更多的第一手资料
that We may learn more about them firsthand.
这不是让你去证明什么 就像之前的一切 只是他们的考验
This isn't prove, it's a test, like everything else.
通过考验的唯一办法 就是回去
The only way to pass, is to go back.
我没法回去了
I can't do that.
我辜负莱恩太多次了
I betrayed Lane's trust too many times.
但每一次 都是你自己的决定
And in every instance, you did so on you own volition.
他打算折磨并杀死一个美国特工
He was going to tortured and killed an American agent.
那你就该帮他啊 这样就还能赢得信任
And you should've let him, and you would still have Lane's trust.
这就是代价 亨特一定能理解的
This is the trade, Hunt understands that.
我不会让他死的 他是我们的同盟
I wasn't going to let him die. He is our ally.
伊尔莎 在政治上 没有同盟 只有共同的利益
There are no allies in state craft, Ilsa. Only common interest.
而且现在 伊森·亨特是一个无国籍人士
As it stands, Ethan Hunt is a man without a country.
所以杀了他不会牵扯到什么复杂的事情
This makes killing him decidedly less complicated.
你是命令我去杀了亨特
Are you ordering me to kill Hunt?
当然不是 我可不会那么残忍
Good god, no. Nothing so crude as that, no.
但莱恩会命令你去的
Lane will order you.
而为了重获他的信任 你必须照做
And to regain his trust, you will do it.
你让我去执行的任务
You sent me to do a job.
我都完成了
I did it.
现在 该恢复我身份了
Now, you bring me in.
也许我也该提醒你一下 你也是个无国籍人士
Might I remind you, you're without a country of your own.
中情局局长亲自向我询问过你的事
The director of the CIA called me inquiring about you personally.
为了保护你的卧底身份 我当然只能撒谎
Of course to protect your cover, I had to lie.
所以至少在美国方面
So, as far as the Americans are concern,
你是个凶残的杀手 通缉的目标
you're a rogue assassin, a target of opportunity.
没什么人知道你的真实身份
A precious few people know about your true identity.
要是我们不小心忘了就惨了
It would be unfortunate if we forgot.
你没得选择 伊尔莎
You see, there really is no choice, Ilsa.
你必须回去
You're going back.
很高兴你还是站在我们这边
Glad to know you're still with us.
怎么 出了什么事
What? What's happening?
我没办法打开
I can't open it.
什么叫你没法打开
What do you mean you can't open it?
意思就是我永远也打不开
I mean I can't open it, ever.
这是个红盒子
That's a red box.
- 一个什么 - 红盒子
- A what? - It's a red box.
英国政府用它来传输国家机密
The British government uses it to transport national secrets.
听起来不太妙啊
Doesn't sound good.
它有三重加密 除非你有指定人的指纹和视网膜
Meaning it's triple encrypted. You don't get into that thing
以及用他声音说的一段话
unless you have fingerprints, retinal scan,
否则根本别想打开
and a voice phrase spoken by a specific individual.
这个人就是英国首相
The Prime Minister of Great Britain himself.
没错 就是他
Yes, him.
你的意思就是 拿不到账册
So, what you're saying is, there is no ledger.
也就是说 没有能证明辛迪加存在的证据
which means we have no proof that the Syndicate even exist.
那我们还得重头再来
So, we're back to square one.
而且现在 我们都被中情局通缉了
Only now, we're all wanted by the CIA.
真为我们骄傲
I'm so proud of us.
我没想通的是 为什么红盒子
What I don't understand is why is there a red box
会存在摩洛哥的一个私人数据库里
sat in a private data vault in Morocco?
为什么莱恩会要一个他根本打不开的东西
And why would Lane want it if he can't open it?
如果莱恩想得到这个 那他肯定有办法打开
If Lane wants it, you can bet that he has a plan to open it.
而我们还帮他偷了出来
And we just help him steal it.
他打算绑架英国首相
He's going to take the Prime Minister.
没错
Yes, he is.
问题是怎么绑架
The question is how?
我们得去警告英国政府
Well, we have to warn the British government.
- 没错 军情六处 - 不 勃兰特
- Yeah, MI6. - No, no, Brandt.
把电话先放下 让我们好好考虑一下
Put down the phone. Let's think about this.
我们有责任通知英国政府
We have a responsibility to warn the British government,
而不是拿首相的命做赌注
and not gamble with the Prime Minister's life.
伊森 那个你想战胜的人
Ethan, just so you can beat the guy
每次交锋都是他赢了
that's beaten you at every turn.
你就是这么想的吗
Is that what you think this is?
勃兰特
Brandt?
你们是这么想的吗
Is that what you think this is?
我是说现在
I think right now,
你没有别的路可选
you're incapable of seeing that there's another way.
但有时候 伊森是唯一一个能看到出路的人
And sometimes Ethan is the only one capable of seeing the only way.
但如果他错了 维也纳的悲剧
And if he's wrong, then we have Vienna
就会重蹈覆辙
all over again.
你一点都不了解他 他想做的事情
No, you don't know him. If he wants something to happen,
没人拦得住
there's no preventing it.
所以我们才要通知英国政府啊
That's why we have to warn the British.
也许这样才正中他下怀呢
Maybe that's exactly what he wants us to do.
你真的慎重考虑了吗 我们应该通知英国政府
Are you listening to yourself? We're going to warn the British.
不 我们应该要找到莱恩
No. We're going to find Lane, we're going to get him.
在他绑架首相之前逮到他
Before he takes the Prime Minister.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 伊森我们要找到莱恩
Alright, Ethan. We're going to find Lane.
但你告诉我
But please tell me.
我们应该怎么做呢
How're we going to do that?
之前的事我就不追究了
All is forgiven.
那个并不是账册 对吗
That isn't a ledger, is it?
你自己没打开先看看吗
You didn't take a look for yourself?
当然看了
Of course I did.
但文件被加密了
But the file was encrypted.
那我为什么要骗你
And why would I lie to you?
这样我就能误导亨特
So that I would lie to Hunt.
但如果他知道那是什么的话 就不会去偷了
But he wouldn't have stolen it if he knew what it was.
而你也不会帮他
And you wouldn't have helped him.
那个移动硬盘里到底有什么
What is actually on that disk?
等你对我坦白的时候 我自然会告诉你
I'll be honest with you when you start being honest with me.
你我心里都清楚 你回来的目的
And you and I, we both know why you come back.
对吧
Don't we?
因为我觉得你还有潜力 才让你活着
You're still alive because I believe in your potential.
但我的耐心是有限的
But I'm growing impatient.
为什么你还要继续挣扎呢
Why do you continue to resist?
那我们就敞开来说吧
Well, if we're being honest,
你是个恐怖分子
You're a terrorist.
如果真如你说的话 我应该传播恐怖言论才对
If that were true then my goal would be to spread fear, but my…
但我的手段… 可要高明多了
method is… far more surgical.
你在滥杀无辜
You kill innocent people.
我帮助我的政府杀了很多无辜的人 而且比这多得多
I helped my government killed many innocent people and more, so much more.
要有杀戮才能维持住一些事情
Killing to keep things as they were.
而现在我杀人是为变革
And now I'm killing to bring about change.
我想伊森·亨特不会同意的
I think Ethan Hunt would disagree.
伊森·亨特就是个赌徒
Ethan Hunt is a gambler.
等到哪天他的运气用光了
And one day his luck will run out,
无数无辜的人会因为他付出生命代价的
And thousands of innocent people will pay the price.
我们谁更像个反派呢
Which one of us will be the villain then?
这里面什么都没有 是空的
Nothing here. It's empty.
我很好奇 你觉得是谁
I'm interested to see who you blame
该为接下来发生的一切负责
for what happens next.
是她吗
So, that's her?
就是她
That's her.
我不得不说
I have to say,
你的骑车技术很厉害
you sure can ride.
- 伊森 - 你只是在完成你的工作
- Ethan. - You're just doing your job.
我就想说这么多
That's all I'm going to say about it.
艾德礼说你会理解的
Attlee said you'd understand.
艾德礼 你在英国情报机关的上司么
Attlee, your handler in British Intelligence.
就算你给了他那个移动硬盘
And he didn't bring you in?
他都不让你全身而退吗
Even after you gave him the disk?
你很清楚那个硬盘是空的
You knew perfectly well it was blank.
她在说谎
That's a lie.
我很确定 她从我这儿拿走的硬盘和备份内容一模一样
The disk she took from me was an exact copy, I'm sure of it.
那个硬盘你一直随身携带吗
Was it in your possession the entire time?
他们根本不在乎你的死活
They don't care if you live or die.
但你知道我会把这个交给他
But you knew I was going to take it to him.
我希望你这么做
I hope you would.
这样你就能全身而退了
I hope it would be enough to get you out.
也就是说
That means Lane
莱恩没有移动硬盘 只有我们有
doesn't have the disk, only we do.
我有个问题 如果硬盘是空的
I have a question. If the disk was blank,
她怎么还活着
why is she still alive?
当然 除非
Unless, of course,
莱恩想让我们找到她
Lane wanted us to find her.
那你现在为谁工作
So, who're you working for now?
莱恩 艾德礼 你的政府 我的政府 他们都一样
Lane, Attlee, your government, my government, they're all the same.
我们都选择坚信自己为之奋斗的是正义的一方
We only think we're fighting for the right side because that's what we choose to believe.
那我们还有什么选择的余地吗
So what does that leave us?
在我看来 你有三个选择
The way I see it, you have 3 choices.
第一 把我供出来 将硬盘交给中情局
One, you hand me and the disk over to the CIA.
我会证明辛迪加存在
I'm proof that Syndicate exist.
莱恩就成了他们的目标 而你的工作也完成了
Lane becomes their problem, and… your work is done.
- 我也是这么想的 - 我也是
- My thoughts exactly. - Works for me.
但你知道 他们不会相信你
But you know they're not going to believe you.
然后你们所有人都会被判叛国罪
And you all will be trialed for treason.
莱恩依旧逍遥法外
Lane goes free.
我觉得她说的没错
I'm afraid she's has a point.
第二 你放我走 让我去面对未知的一切
Two, you let me walk away to an uncertain fate.
接着用这个硬盘去引诱莱恩上钩
You use the disk as bait to trap Lane.
但是你内心深处又害怕棋逢敌手
But some part of you suspect you've met your match.
这样冒险赌一把 硬盘最终很有可能落入莱恩手中
And being a gambler, you'll probably end up handing Lane that disk
不管你情愿与否
whether you want to or not.
这完全有可能
That is entirely possible.
第三个选择呢
And option three?
和我一起远走高飞
Come away with me.
就现在
Right now.
噢 天啊
Oh boy.
那莱恩怎么办
And what about Lane?
别管什么莱恩了
Forget about Lane.
一个莱恩倒了 也会有第二个莱恩出现
There will always be another Lane.
总会有像我们这样的人去对付他
There will always be people like us to face him.
我们已经完成了任务 却被抛弃
We've done our part and we've been cast aside.
我们可以是任何人
We can be anyone.
做任何想做的事
We can do anything.
这只取决于你是走是留
It's only a matter of going.
是莱恩派你过来传信的 对吧
Lane sent you to deliver a message, didn't he?
我已经救了你两次 不可能再救你了
I saved you life twice. I won't be able to do it again.
他想告诉我什么
What's the message?
班吉
Benji.
地下车库
Parking garage
卢瑟 跟紧她
Luther, stay with her.
她跑掉了
She's gone.
我把她跟丢了
I lost her.
她给我们下了个套 伊森
She set us up, Ethan.
不 她只是传信而已
No, she delivered a message.
她耍了我们
She set us up!
她早知道计划是这样
She knew this would happen.
只有莱恩知道会发生什么
Only Lane knows what's going to happen.
我有个任务给你 伊森
I have a job for you, Ethan.
为了你的朋友 你会答应的
And for the sake of your friend, you will do it.
我在听
I'm listening.
你有权选择是否接受这个任务
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
今晚午夜 把移动硬盘破解后交到我手上
Is to bring me the unlocked disk by midnight today.
现在 请说出你的决定吧
Now say the words, please.
我接受
I accept.
很好
Yes.
如我所料
I knew you would.
他想要那个硬盘 破解后的 今晚午夜之前
He wants the disk, unlocked, by midnight tonight
伊森 这世界上只有一个人能解锁那个硬盘
Ethan, there's only one person on earth who can unlock that disk.
我们必须得绑架首相
We have to take the Prime Minister.
我们再好好考虑下吧
Let's just think about that for a minute.
这是能救回班吉的唯一办法
That's the only way to get Benji back.
伊森 这么做正中莱恩下怀
Ethan, that's exactly what Lane wants you to do.
所以 不管怎样都只能如此
Which is why it has to happen.
这是我们打败莱恩的机会
This is how we beat Lane.
是让一切都重回正轨的机会
This is how we make everything right.
你知道了吗 明白吗
Can you see? Can you see it?
长官 威廉·勃兰特的电话 他说有紧急情况
William Brandt, sir. He says it's urgent.
我就知道你会想通的 勃兰特
I had a feeling you'd come to your senses, Brandt.
要不是实在走投无路了 我是不会打给你的
I'm only calling you because I've no other choice.
我要阻止一场灾难
I'm trying to prevent a catastrophe.
我完全理解 你现在在哪
I can understand that. Where are you?
- 伦敦 - 掉头去伦敦 立刻
- London - Reroute us to London, now.
- 伦敦哪里 - 现在还不能说 等下了飞机再告诉你
- Where in London? - I'll tell you when you land, not before.
我可没心思陪你玩游戏 勃兰特
I'm not interested in playing games, Brandt.
我也没心思眼睁睁看着我的朋友被害
And I'm not interested in seeing my friends get killed either.
所以 如果要我背叛他们 就要按我的方法来
So if I'm going to betray them, we're going to do this in my terms
只能照我说的做 明白吗
and my terms only. Do you understand?
保持电话通畅 随后给你指示
Keep your phone on, instruction will follow.
- 差不多该走了吧 - 对
- Should have been gone by now. - Yeah.
- 你还好吗 - 嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
我们今晚就要绑架英国首相了
We're suppose to take down the Prime Minister of Great Britain tonight.
所以
So…
勃兰特
Brandt.
我实在想不到别的办法了
I can't see another way.
我也是
Neither can I.
但我们所做的一切都是为了朋友 对吗
What we do, we have to do for our friends, right?
让他准备好
Get him ready, please.
勃兰特 打给我是明智之举 亨特在哪
You're right to call me, Brandt. Where is Hunt?
他在来的路上 我们没有多少时间
He's on his way. We don't have much time.
- 他到底想干什么 - 重要的是他还活着
- What does he intend to do? - What matter is he's alive.
而且我需要你保证他的人身安全
And I need your reassurance that it's going to stay that way.
亨特要对首相下手这个消息 你通知英国政府了吗
Have you informed the British Government that Hunt has targeted the Prime Minister?
我会帮你捉到他 活捉 仅此而已
I will help you capture him… alive. That is the deal.
勃兰特 你从你朋友身上沾染到了一些坏习惯
You picked up some terrible habits from your friend, Brandt
而最坏的一个就是 你居然以为自己能掌控全局
The worst of them being that you still believe you can control any outcome.
跟着他
Stay with him.
艾德礼局长 艾德礼局长
Chief Attlee. Chief Attlee.
亨利局长 真高兴能在这遇到你
Director Hunley, how delightful to see you here.
上次我们通话时 你正在摩洛哥抓一个叛逃的特工吧
Last time we spoke, you were hunting rogue agents in Morocco.
艾德礼局长 我有证据表明首相大人正处于危险当中
Chief Attlee, I have reason to believe that the Prime Minister's life is in danger.
请讲
I'm listening.
有比两万二出价更高的吗 有吗
Any advance on 22, 000? Anyone?
两万二一次 两万二两次
Going once. Going twice.
成交 慷概的首相夫人竞得
Sold! To our generous Chairwoman.
长官 军情六处的艾德礼局长要见您
Sir. Chief Attlee from MI6 needs to see you.
他说是紧急情况
He says it's urgent.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
- 这是怎么回事 - 先生 事关国家安全
- What's this all about? - It's a matter of national security, Sir.
- 不论任何情况 任何人都不许进来 - 是的 长官
- Under no circumstances is anyone to enter. - Yes sir.
给我解释一下
Help me to understand.
那个人是谁 他为什么要绑架我
Who is this man? Why is he after me?
首相 恐怕亨利局长和我都难辞其咎
I'm afraid, Prime Minister, Director Hunley and I share responsibility for this.
伊森·亨特是一个让我们蒙羞的情报组织的特工
Ethan Hunt was part of a disgrace intelligence agency which is since been dissolved.
组织一解散 他就叛逃了 他一心想
And he's gone rogue, unfortunately intend on
企图捣毁一个并不存在的恐怖犯罪组织
dismantling an imaginary terror network.
但是最新情报表明
But new intelligence suggest that he's been
他一直被你们国家的一位前特工操纵
manipulated by one of your own former agents.
首相大人 是伊尔莎·福斯特 她在两年前失踪了
Ilsa Faust, Prime Minister. She disappeared 2 years ago.
不介意的话我想问一下
And if you don't mind I asking,
我跟这个神秘组织有什么关系
what do I have to do with this phantom network?
先生 这位是威廉·勃兰特 亨特以前的同事
Sir, this is William Brandt, a former colleague of Hunt's.
他将为您解释 关于这个针对您的阴谋的情报
He came forward with first hand knowledge of the plot against you.
先生 亨特有一个只能由您打开的虚拟红盒子
Sir. Hunt is in possession of a virtual red box that can only be open by you.
他认为这是捣毁辛迪加组织的关键
He believes it is the key to bring down the Syndicate.
- 你是说 辛迪加 - 是的 先生 他就是这么说的
- The Syndicate, you say? - Yes, Sir. That's what he calls it.
艾德礼
Attlee.
他说的不会是那个「辛迪加」吧
He couldn't possibly be talking about that "Syndicate"?
我记得你向我保证过 那个「辛迪加」只是个实验吧
'Cause you assured me that, that "Syndicate" was merely an exercise?
那确实是 我能向您保证
And it was, Prime Minister. I can assure you.
但是 中情局说明的情况好像并不是这样
And yet, here we have the Central Intelligence Agency indicating otherwise.
- 我不太明白 - 首相大人 您正处于危险当中
- I don't understand. - Prime Minister, your life is in danger.
我认为我们的首要任务是把您转移至安全的地方
I think our first priority is to move you to a secure location.
先生 所罗门·莱恩这个名字 您听着有印象吗
Sir. Does the name, Solomon Lane, ring a bell?
很不幸 我记得这个名字
Yes. Unfortunately, it does.
所以 辛迪加是真实存在的
So, there actually is a Syndicate?
这是艾德礼局长设想的一个雏形
It was a hypothetical brainchild of Chief Attlee.
招募其他国家退役的特工 给他们新的身份
Recruit former agents from other nations. supply them with a new identity
利用他们除掉我们国内外的敌人
and use them to surgically remove our enemies, both at home and abroad.
所有的执行预算都藏在海外一个
Its operating budget was to be hidden offshore
只有我能打开的红盒子里
in a virtual red box which I alone would control.
这项目让我集法官 陪审 执行者这三种角色于一身
It would have made me judge, jury, and executioner,
并且责任全免
with zero accountability.
我一开始就坚决反对了这项提议
I rejected the proposal unequivocally.
而且 有人还向我保证 这项目永远不会执行
Furthermore, I was given every assurance it never pass the planning stage.
首相大人 辛迪加根本就不存在
Prime Minister, there is no any Syndicate.
这些人都被福斯特特工给骗了
These people have been duped by agent Faust.
艾德礼 把这套说辞留到听证会吧
Attlee. Save it for the public inquiry.
先生 我建议您不要离开这间屋子
Sir, I urge you not to leave this room.
- 不好意思 - 请您考虑一下
- Excuse me. - Please.
亨特是经过特别训练的人 而且不达目的誓不罢休
Hunt is uniquely trained and highly motivated.
没有人能与他抗衡 他也不露出任何破绽
A specialist without equal, immune to any counter measures.
没有他拿不到的情报 也没有他越不过的防线
There is no secret he cannot extract. No security he cannot breach.
也没有他伪装不了的人
No person he cannot become.
而且他有可能已经猜到会有这段对话
He has mostly likely anticipated this very conversation
正等着我们转移时袭击
and is waiting to strike in whatever direction we move.
先生 亨特他不会善罢甘休的
Sir. Hunt is the living manifestation of destiny.
而您 现在是他的目标
And he has made you his mission.
首相大人
Prime Minister.
亨特
Hunt.
长官 请离开首相大人
Sir, please step away from the Prime Minister.
先生 请放松 一切都在掌控之中
Just relax, Sir. Everything is going to be alright.
- 艾德礼朝我开了一枪 - 是的 就是他
- Attlee shot me - Yes, he did, Sir.
亨特 你要知道你这么做会把美英关系拉回到独立战争时期
Hunt, I hope you realize you set back US, UK relations to the American revolution.
长官 特殊时期 特殊处理
Desperate times, desperate measures, sir.
- 我在 - 随时待命
- I'm here. - Standby to receive.
准备就绪
Ready.
首相秘书通知我来见他
The Prime Minister's office ask me to meet him here.
先生 这边走
This way, sir
扫描中
Scanning.
虹膜扫描 确认
Retinal scan, confirm.
一会儿就好了 先生
Some convenience, Sir.
你的手好暖啊
You got a very warm hand.
指纹认证 确认
Biometric, confirm.
- 语音提示是「吉普林」 - 语音提示是「吉普林」
- The prompt is "KIPLING". - The prompt is "KIPLING".
先生 我需要一个解密口令 提示是「吉普林」
Sir, I'm gonna need a pass phrase, the prompt is "KIPLING".
当然
Yes, of course.
「如果所有人都失去理智 咒骂你 你仍能保持头脑清醒」
" If you can keep your head when all about you. Are losing theirs…"
「如果所有人都怀疑你 你仍能相信自己」
" If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you "
- 好了吗 - 好了
- You got it? - I got it.
天呐 全都搞到了
Oh man, do I got it.
- 我来见首相大人 - 我们收到命令 任何人都不能进入
- I'm here to see the Prime Minister. - We were told not to let anybody in.
- 谁的命令 - 你的啊 长官
- By whom? - By you, sir.
亨利 这是怎么回事 警卫
Hunley, what is this? Security!
艾德礼局长 你能来赴约真是太好了
Chief Attlee. Kind of you to accepted our invitation.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
我们知道你创造了辛迪加
We know you created the Syndicate.
但是莱恩叛逃了 把它变成了反抗你的组织 是不是
But Lane went rogue and turn it against you, didn't he?
而你 一直急于掩盖这个事实
And you've been desperately trying to cover it up.
这就是为什么她把硬盘交给你的时候 你把内容清除了
That's why you erased the disk which she brought it to you.
说的没错
That's true.
现在 亨利局长有关于伊尔莎·福斯特的问题要问你
Now, Director Hunley has some questions for you regarding Ilsa Faust.
换句话说 你是怎么陷害她的
Namely, how you frame her.
这也是真的
That's also true.
这是解药
It's the antidote.
当首相发现关于辛迪加的真相的时候
When the Prime Minister found out about the Syndicate.
- 艾德礼攻击了他 - 是的 没错
- Attlee had attacked him. - Yes, that's true.
长官 是你救了首相
And then you saved the Prime Minister, sir.
是吗
Did he?
感激不尽
I'm very grateful.
长官
Sir.
伊森 你快要完成任务了
You're cutting it very close, Ethan
我拿到你想要的东西了 我该去哪碰头
I have what you want. Where do I go?
伊森 等等
Ethan, wait
如果我没在十五分钟内赶到 他会杀了班吉的
If I'm not there in 15 minutes, he'll kill Benji.
你的任务是捣毁辛迪加
The mission is to bring down the Syndicate.
如果莱恩拿到了这些资金
If Lane gets his hands on that money,
我们就相当于造就了一个超级恐怖集团
we're unleashing a terrorist superpower.
他不会活捉到我的 这点我可以确定
He'll never take me alive. I'll make sure of it.
那如果你不能安全回来呢
What happens, Ethan, if you can't make it back?
我一定会回来的
I'll make it back.
准备好吧
Just be ready.
向您致以诚挚的问候 首相大人 如果您正在观看这则信息
Greetings, Prime Minister. If you are viewing this message,
那就说明您选择启动辛迪加计划
it means that you have chosen to activate the Syndicate.
这张盘可以让您控制无法追查的二十四亿英镑的使用权限
This drive gives you access to 2.4 billion pound sterling in untraceable currency.
这些资金可以让辛迪加项目秘密运作达数十年
That will allow the Syndicate to operate undetected for decades.
获取资金的步骤如下
Instructions to access these funds are as follows.
亨特先生 一切都要结束了
This is the end, Mr. Hunt.
小心
Carefully.
两磅塑胶炸药 五百三十口径的滚珠承轴
2 pounds of Semtex, 530 caliber ball bearings.
你的朋友正坐在一个高敏压力触发器上
Your friend is sitting on a highly sensitive-pressure trigger.
所以 别轻举妄动
So, no sudden moves.
这是你的终极考验
Your final test.
等莱恩拿到他想到的东西 我就杀了你和班吉
When Lane has what he wants, I kill you and Benji.
如果拿不到 所有人都得死
If not, everyone dies.
没时间考虑了 伊森 请坐下来吧
No time to think, Ethan. Have a seat, please.
人性啊 我选择的武器
Human nature, my weapon of choice.
从我在音像店杀死那个年轻姑娘开始
From the moment I killed the young lady in the record shop,
我就知道你会不顾一切来抓我
I knew you would stop at nothing to catch me.
我也知道伊尔莎没有别的选择
I also knew Ilsa wouldn't have a choice.
无论是她那晚上制服你还是有意放你走
Whether she broke you that night you met or let you go.
不管你有没有在摩洛哥放走她 也不管她到底见没见艾德礼
Whether you let her run in Morocco. Whether she went to Attlee or not.
你都确定我们一定会走到现在这一步 在此时此地了结
You were certain we would end up where we are… right now.
不过话说回来
Then again.
我的武器也一样
So was I.
我了解你 莱恩
I know you, Lane.
一直徘徊在道德边界 你有了信仰危机
Somewhere along the line you had a crisis of faith.
从此人命对你来说轻若鸿毛 也许在你眼里也从未重要过
Human life didn't matter anymore, or maybe it never really did.
不管怎样 你杀了太多无辜的人
Either way, you killed too many innocent people
却从不质问谁下达的命令
without ever asking who was giving the orders or why.
也不问为什么
Or why.
你把变成现在这样的原因归咎于制度
You blame the system for what you are.
而不是你自己
Instead of yourself.
你想报复
You wanted revenge.
但冰冻三尺 非一日之寒
But Rome wasn't destroyed in a day.
你需要帮助 需要大量资金
You needed help, you needed the money. A lot of it.
而且你会不择手段的得到这些
And you'll stop at nothing to get it.
所以 我知道我会让你自投罗网
That's how I know I'm going to put you in a box.
- 硬盘在哪 - 硬盘在哪
- Where is the disk? - Where is the disk?
你不是喜欢玩游戏吗 我给你准备了一个
You like to play games. I've a game for you.
我打算给你五千万美元
I'll give you 50 million dollars
放班吉走
to let Benji go.
- 硬盘在哪 - 硬盘在哪
- Where is the disk? - Where is the disk?
你正看着呢 我就是那个硬盘
You're looking at it. I am the disk.
我记住了那些二十四亿英镑的所有数字账号
I memorized it all 2.4 billion in number accounts.
如果炸弹引爆 你就什么也得不到
If that vest goes off, you get nothing.
没有了这笔钱 你什么都不是
Without this money, you're nothing.
没有了我 你什么也干不了
Without me, you are nothing.
也许现在你觉得我只是虚张声势 我绝不会让我的朋友去死
Right now, you're thinking it's bluff. I'd never let my friends die.
我不可能记住硬盘里的全部账户
I couldn't possibly memorize the entire disk.
确定这些 只有一个办法
There's only one way to be sure.
让班吉走
Let Benji go
抓住他
Take him.
他们再靠近一步 就朝我开枪
They come 1 step closer, shoot me.
停下
Stop.
你记得我和你说过 总有一天你的运气会用完吗
You remember I told you, one day you were going to take things too far?
提醒一下 这是我在说话 不是他
This is me speaking, by the way. It's not him.
只有我和你 面对面解决 莱恩 才能结束这一切
The only way this ends is you and me, Lane, face to face.
只是这一次我不是被锁在玻璃箱子里
Only this time I won't be locked in a glass box.
你不是想拿走你的钱吗
You want your money.
那就让骨科医生再来拷问我
The bone doctor is going to beat it out of me.
现在 放班吉走
Now let Benji go
一 三 九
1… 3… 9…
快走
Go.
- 伊森 - 勃兰特和卢瑟在等你 快走
- Ethan. - Brandt and Luther are waiting. Go.
- 接下来做什么 - 杀了那个女人
- What do I do? - Kill the woman.
给我活捉亨特
I need Hunt alive.
- 说 - 我是班吉 我该去哪
- Go! - It's Benji, where am I going?
- 他们来了 - 我们还没准备好呢
- They're coming. - We're not ready.
那就快准备
Then get ready.
哪边走
Which way?
面对面较量 如你所愿 伊森
Face to face. Just as you wish, Ethan
很不爽吧 我懂这种滋味
It hurts, I know.
各位 这就是所罗门·莱恩
Gentlemen, this is Solomon Lane.
莱恩先生
Mr. Lane.
我们是碟中谍小组
Meet the IMF.
你现在自由了
You're free now.
你会去哪儿
Where will you go?
我不知道
I don't know.
我已经完成了我的任务
I've done my part.
是啊
Yeah.
伊森 我们得走了
Ethan, we got to go.
你最好快点
You better hurry now.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你知道怎么找到我
You know how to find me.
亨利局长
Director Hunley.
- 亨利局长 - 呃 主席先生
- Director Hunley. - Ah… Mr. Chairman.
六个月之前 你在议会议员面前 要求解散碟中谍小组
6 months ago, you stood before this panel and demanded that the IMF be dissolved.
是的 先生
That is correct, sir.
那你怎么解释今天的证词
And how do you explain your testimony today?
其实很简单 我们有理由相信
It's quite simple really. We had reason to believe
辛迪加已经渗透到政府的最高层
that the Syndicate have infiltrated our government at the highest level.
为了让我们的人潜入那个组织 他的卧底身份必须万全
In order for our men to infiltrate that organization, his cover had to be absolute.
整个行动只有我和少数碟中谍小组的成员知道
The whole operation was known only to myself and a handful of IMF agents.
所以碟中谍小组的解散 只是这个计划的一部分
So, the shuttering of the IMF was all part of an elaborate scheme.
- 就为了揭露这个所谓的辛迪加 - 是的 先生
- To expose this so call Syndicate? - That is correct, sir.
所以这也是你今天来的原因 请求恢复碟中谍小组
Which is why you're here today, asking for the IMF to be reinstated.
是的 先生
That is correct, sir.
亨利局长 我不确定委员会是否赞同你这种做法
I'm not sure the Committee approves of your methods, Director Hunley.
特殊时期 特殊对待 主席先生
Desperate times, desperate measures, Mr. Chairman.
你呢 勃兰特先生
And you, Mr. Brandt.
你怎么解释这次的欺瞒行为
How can you justify this deception?
在没有获得部长的许可之前
I can neither confirm nor deny details of any operation
我既不能承认也不能否认这些行动的细节
without the Secretary's approval.
欢迎加入碟中谍小组
Welcome to the IMF.
部长先生
Mr. Secretary.